I'm on TRT and HCG. Should I take
Nulvidex or Tamoxifen for gynecomastia?
I've already done surgery for Janikcomia
before.
So, questions like this are basically
like, you know, do I want you to punch
me or kick me in the face? Um,
neither. Um, so it's a closed question,
but the answer is is is neither. So if
you've had gynecomastia surgery
previously and you're still getting
gynecomastia growth on TRT, it generally
means one of the following if not both.
Is that one the surgery was not done
properly and they didn't remove the
entire gland. I I've heard surgeons
often say, "Oh, you can't remove the
entire gland." Maybe they can't, but
other surgeons can. That's it's called a
skill issue. But I've heard other
surgeons say, "Oh, well, if you remove
the whole gland, the nipple will cave
in." There's two massive flaws to this.
One, men who don't have gyno, don't have
caved in nipples. This is what happens
to women. But number two, I'd rather
have does any man care if their nipple
is caved in? Like really, no one cares.
We just don't want gyno. So that's not a
problem. It's it's it's a skill issue.
So you need to find a surgeon who will
take the whole thing out. But with that
said,
this is typically a problem that guys
have when they're abusing steroids
because on TRT typically if gyno becomes
present, it's flaring up gynecomastia
that was there already from when they
were hypogonatal. This is when
gynecomastia occurs when you have low
levels of androgens. You high levels of
androgens within the physiological range
don't cause men to grow female mammorary
glands. It's just not how biology works.
So, if you're in a situation where
you've had the majority of the gina
removed and you're on TRT and it keeps
coming back, there's something wrong
with the overall health or the protocol.
And something that often causes this is
guys are using, you know, higher doses
of TRT and they might not be injecting
it often enough, but they've got
underlying issues that are leading to
elevated levels of prolactin and
estrogen together, which is typically,
and again, this is not saying you need
to use an AI or you need to use these
medications. It's typically an issue
with liver problems, too much alcohol,
or insulin resistance. So if you're in a
situation where you're highly insulin
resistant and you're taking a large
amount of testosterone and you're prone
to gynecomastia, then that can continue
the growth of gyno because you're
putting a very large amount of
testosterone into an environment that
wouldn't usually have it and it's like
pouring gasoline on a fire that you've
only partially put out. So I would be
getting comprehensive blood work done
with someone who knows how to assess for
these things. Hypothyroidism can also be
a factor that can impact it a little
bit, but it would have to be pretty
severe, but I would be looking at
alternate routes. Both tmoxifen and
Clomid cause uh non-alcoholic fatty
liver disease. Um they also make you
that both of them will make you feel
terrible and if you took them in a dose
high enough to prevent gynecomastia
growth, you would solve one problem but
probably create 10 more in the process.
So, I would uh take a left when you're
taking a right